Finding Aid for the Brian Urquhart Collection of Material about Ralph Bunche, ca. 1932-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Speeches & Writings 3, (Including Race)., 1955-1959.; [Box 31, 4 folders]
  - R.J. Bunche remarks at Brown University convocation on Man in a Contracting World in an Expanding Universe., October 22, 1959. (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Speeches & Writings 4., 1960-1964.; [Box 31, 5 folders]
  - Galley: Recent Middle East Developments Involving the UN., March 9, 1960. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Transcript: National Education TV Program no.6-- Africa: Revolution in Haste., March 14, 1960. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Wellesley College Symposium on Africa., March 16-17, 1960. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - East-West Relations., 1960. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Galleys:The UN and the Middle East (); UN Grows Steadily Stronger (); Africa & UN (); UN Approach to Underdeveloped Areas ()., March 26, 1960 March 21, 1960 April 18, 1960 April 1960. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Emergence of American Negro., March 13, 1961. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Emerging Africa & UN., March 23, 1961. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Galley: Challenge of Modern Africa., April 17, 1961. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - The Individual & the Quest for Peace., May 22, 1961. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Press clippings., June 1961. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - International Cooperation in Search for Peace., July 25, 1961. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Galley: Tribute of Heinz Weischhoff., October 25, 1961. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Galleys: Prospects for Effective International Authority (); UN & Peace in Africa (); Education & Teachers ()., February 13, 1962 April 10, 1962 May 4, 1962. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - UN & Congo (); University Glasgow Honorary Degree Ceremony ()., April 3, 1962 June 20, 1962. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche speech to United Auto Workers 18th Constitutional Convention., May 7, 1962. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Galley: Youth Night at 53rd NAACP Convention re Negro's Struggle for Equality., July 6, 1962. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Galleys: UN in Congo: Fallacy & Truth (); Africa Tests the UN (); World Peace & Religion ()., February 17, 1963 May 3, 1963 May 18, 1963. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Speech to VA Council on Human Relations, ()., February 23, 1963. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Colgate University Commencement Address., June 10, 1963. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Letters/article re Chapman College Talk., April 1963. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Long Island Press interview transcript., June 9, 1963. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche at 51st anniversary of July 4th celebration., July 4, 1963.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - UN in 1963., October 23, 1963. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Speaking of Holiday., 1963, 1964[?]. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Annual Printing Week dinner., January 16, 1964. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Letters/articles re civil rights includes letter to M.L. King., 1964. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - NAACP World March Toward Human Rights., May 28, 1964. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Galley: Peacemaking & UN., May 8, 1964. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Galley: Visiting scholar lecture San Jose State., November 5, 1964. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - UN operation in Congo., March 16, 1964. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Speech Claremont Men's College., May 7, 1964. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - University Maine Commencement Address., June 5, 1964. (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Speeches & Writings 5., 1965-1970.; [Box 32, 4 folders]
  - March on Montgomery from Selma., March 25, 1965. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - "Speech, "March on Montgomery from Selma", 25 March 1965, Montogomery, Alabama". (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Some current dangers & hopes., April 21, 1965. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche interview., April 13, 1966. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - One Man's Outlook., May 31, 1965. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche statement on rioting in Los Angeles., August 17, 1965. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Galley: City of Hope National Convention address., July 12, 1965. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Notes for R.J. Bunche's Manila speech., August 13, 1965. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Age of Unprecedented Peace & War., June 5, 1966.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche statement at IAEA General conference, Vienna., September 21, 1966. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Paper: Reactions to racial disturbances in our cities., July 31, 1967. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Two Critical American Dilemmas: Vietnam & the Ghetto., February 21, 1968. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Paper: Black Revolution., August 20, 1968. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - UCLA Alumni Magazine includes An interview with R.J. Bunche 1927., Winter 1968, 1969.; (Original copy) (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche on Bunche Hall Dedication., May 23, 1969. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Transcripts: NBC's Today Show w/R.J. Bunche (); R.J. Bunche remarks at Press Briefing ()., February 20, 1969 1970. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche interview w/ The Nigerian Journal., Winter 1969. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Psychology Today includes interview M.Harrington Hall-R.J. Bunche Psychology of Humanity., April 1969. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Race & Alienation., July 10, 1969. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Transcript: ABC's Issues & Answers., December 28, 1969. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Press briefing., July 1, 1970. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - 9th Editor's Roundtable hears UN & Peacekeeping., October 20, 1970. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - J.D. Weaver's R.J. Bunche: Early Years & R.J. Bunche: Seasons of Influence., June 1975. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - New Yorker Talk of the Town., January 1, 1972. (Box 32, Folder 6)
- Index, Speeches, Articles, Interviews., [Box 33, 1 folder]
  - R.J. Bunche indexes re childhood, personal philosophy, Nobel prize, loyalty board hearings, UN, Middle East, Africa/colonialism/trusteeship, Congo, Korea, China, Vietnam, atomic energy, peace/war. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche indexes re nationalism, East-West conflict, developing countries, human relations, morality, education, race, Black Revolution, democracy/democracy & race, youth, and UCLA papers. (Box 33, Folder 1)
- List of Articles on Ralph J. Bunche., 1949-1969.; [Box 33, 1 folder]
  - Press clippings lists. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - New York Times Indexes. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche & atomic energy, International relations/missions, UN, Africa/decolonization, and general., 1949-1969. (Box 33, Folder 2)
- Ralph J. Bunche Clippings., 1946-1971.; [Box 33, 17 folders]
  - Dr.Bunche Blames Our Schools for Our Prejudices, F.M. Hechinger. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Ralph Bunche - Statesman. The Reporter., December 6, 1949. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Ralph Bunche - American Peacemaker R.B. Gehman in Saturday Evening Post., June 11, 1949. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Bunche Vacations After 8 Years (original). Minneapolis Morning Tribune., July 4, 1949. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Dr. Bunche, Peacemaker, is Year's Father (original). Father's Day News., June 1-19, 1949. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Coveted Award Goes to Dr. Bunche (original). Washington Afro-American., September 26, 1950. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Ralph Bunche: Miracle Man (original). Our World., November 1951. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - America's Most. Ebony., January 1950. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Dr. Ralph Bunche, Recipient of 1950 Nobel Peace Prize, Has Story that Out-Horatios Any Alger Tale Ever Written - An Orphan at 12 V. Irwin. St.Louis Post Dispatch., December 24, 1950. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - 5,000 see Ralph Bunche present BB Award to Mrs. FDR at Westchester UN Rally (original) National Jewish Monthly., December 1952. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Dr.Bunche for Top UN Post (original). Courier., 1952. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Presenting Annual Horatio Alger Awards Here (original). New York Times., April 23, 1952. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Fragment of (original) article: UN Day., 1952. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Fragment of (original) article in New York Herald., 1952. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Settlement of Kashmir Dispute - Bunche hopes for real progress (); Dr. Ralph Bunche works for world peace (); UN will persist in its efforts (); (original) Sind Observer, Karachi., February 3, 1953 February 3, 1953 February 4, 1953. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Dr. Bunche works for world peace R. Chapman. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Bunche arrives in city (original) Civil & Milwaukee Gazette., February 3, 1953. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Bunche in city, pays tributes to Zafrullah (original). Dawn., February 3, 1953. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Post Stamp (original). UN Bulletin., February 1953. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Articles (original). (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - re R.J. Bunche in Auckland Star., June 23, 1954. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - re R.J. Bunche & Einstein Medical School in Jewish Floridian., February 19, 1954. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - re R.J. Bunche's UN appointment World Magazine., May 1954. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - re R.J. Bunche y su raza in Hoy Mag (Spanish)., June 5, 1954. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - re loyalty hearings (), New York Herald., July 2, 1954. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - re discrimination in Worcester Telegram., July 8, 1954. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - re lectures in Chautauquan Daily., August 14, 1954. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - re UN appointment in Christian Science Monitor., August 19, 1954. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - [Miscellaneous]., 1954. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Various original newspaper clippings., 1955. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Photocopies of newspaper clippings., 1957. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Original newspaper clippings. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Original magazine articles. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - R.J. Bunche article in Life International., August 18, 1958.; (Photocopies) (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Original newspaper clippings., 1959. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Photocopies of newspaper clippings., 1959. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Original newspaper clippings., 1960. (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Original magazine articles., 1960. (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Photocopies of newspaper clippings., 1960. (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Mostly original newspaper clippings., 1961. (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Some newspaper clippings., 1961.; (Photocopied) (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper clipping (original). Life magazine article., May 11, 1962.; (Photocopy) (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - New York Times index., 1962. (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - New York Times index., 1963. (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper clippings., (Photocopied) (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Original Pity This Country--Not the Negro Sepia Magazine July 1963. (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Original newspaper clippings., 1963. (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - New York Times index., 1964. (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Original article Uhuru comes to Kenya., March 1964. (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper clipping., 1964.; (Photocopy) (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper clippings., (Photocopies) (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - New York Times Indexes., 1965-1968. (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Original newspaper clippings. (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper clippings., (Photocopies) (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - New York Times Indexes., 1969. (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - New York Times Index., 1971. (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Original newspaper and magazine clippings re R.J. Bunche's death., 1971. (Box 33, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous Speeches, Magazine Articles, Interviews., n.d.; [Box 34, 1 folder]
  - Explosion in Palestine R.J. Bunche w/A. Herzog. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - 10 years of UN in Think magazine (original)., October 1955. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche-Statesman Reporter magazine (original)., December 6, 1949. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Time (original) w/R.J. Bunche article., October 2, 1950. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - New Yorker (original) R.J. Bunche in Talk of Town., January 1, 1972. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Ebony (original) R.J. Bunche: 1904-1971., February 1972. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Life (original) w/R.J. Bunche cover., August 18, 1958. (Box 34, Folder 1)
- Notebook with Biographical Information, (CV, etc.)., [Box 34, 1 folder]
  - Notebook with the following headings: educational background, field research experience, professional employment, International conference, publications, honorary degrees, decorations, awards, schools, miscellaneous honors., 1920s-1970. (Box 34, Folder 2)
- Photographs, (Early Years)., 1971.; [Boxes 35 and 37-38, 26 folders]
  - Listings of photographs from., 1945-1971. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - List of Bunche effects (), R.J. Bunche bust (), and framed photographs (some signed, others not)., 1990 1958. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Mostly copy prints of photographs. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Participants of a conference at Howard University., 1932 April. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Ralph J. Bunche at the First Session, General Assembly, United Nations, London., 1946 January. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Some photocopies of photographs. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - List of photographs:., 1945 (undated), October; 1946: February 21-March 13. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Copy prints of photographs. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Countess Estelle Bernadotte, Count Folke Bernadotte and Ralph J. Bunche at Parkway Village, New York., 1948 August. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Acting U.N. Mediator, Ralph J. Bunche, in Palestine., 1948. (Box 35, Folder 3)
      Dr. Ralph J. Bunche, acting U.N. Mediator for Palestine, in conference with Gen. A. Lundstrom, Chief Military Observer, in Haifa.
  - List of photographs., 1947: March 4, n.d., June 12, July 1, December 4; 1948: January 23-November, some undated. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1949. (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Copy prints of photographs. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Ralph J. Bunche with Henry Moon, Roy Wilkins, and Will Rogers, Jr. at the 1949 NAACP Convention in Los Angeles, Calif., 1949 July. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - List of photographs., January-December 1949. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Copy prints of photographs. (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Gunnar Jahn, Chairman of the Nobel Committee, and Ralph J. Bunche at the 1950 Nobel Prize presentation ceremony., 1950 December 10. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - List of photographs., May-December 1950. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Oversize photographs: R.J. Bunche in garden (); R.J. Bunche w/N.Krumak?; R.J. Bunche & Ruth with Josephine Baker, Walter White, & Poppy Cannon White; R.J. Bunche w/Dean Rusk; two of R.J. Bunche w/J.Baker; Harpo Marx (); R.J. Bunche w/Doreen Daughton, John Redmond, C. Stavropoulos; R.J. Bunche w/family., October 1959 January 1962. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Ralph J. Bunche gardening., 1959 October 19. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Ralph J. Bunche and Josephine Baker., ca. 1960. (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Oversize sketch of R.J. Bunche from Tenampa, Mexico., 1955. (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Photocopy oversize photograph R.J. Bunche w/Nehru, Shaha., December 20, 1956. (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - List of photographs., March-October 29, 1951. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1951. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - List of photographs., February-December 1953. (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1953. (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - List of photographs., December 7, 1954. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1954. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - List of photographs., February 9-December 2, 1955. (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1955. (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - List of photographs., November 16, 1956. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1956. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - List of photographs., March 11 - September/October 1957. (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1957. (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - List of photographs., September 1-13, September, October 1958. (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1958. (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - List of photographs., April 23-December 11, 1959. (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1959. (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - List of photographs., February-September 2, 1960 (some undated). (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Copy prints of photographs. (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Photographs., 1960.; (Photocopies) (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - List of photographs., September 25-December 21, 1961 (some undated). (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1961. (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - List of photographs., February 7-October 22, 1962. (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1962. (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - List of photographs., January 9-December 17, 1963. (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1963. (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - List of photographs., January 11-December 17, 1964. (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1964. (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. and Coretta Scott King visit United Nations Headquarters., 1964. (Box 37, Folder 13)
      Dr. King and his wife, Coretta King, are being greeted at U.N. Headquarters by Ralph J. Bunche, U.N. Under-Secretary for Special Political Affairs.
    - Ralph J. Bunche visits Cyprus., 1964 April 10. (Box 37, Folder 13)
      Ralph Bunche, U.N. Under-Secretary for Special Political Affairs, visited Nicosia, Cyprus in the course of routine visits to Gaza and Kashmir to study the problems and needs of the United Nations truce supervision and peace force operations in these areas. In this photograph, Bunche meets Turkish Cypriots in the refugee camp at Hamitkoy, near Nicosia.
  - List of photographs., April 14-December, 1965. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Copy prints of photographs. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Cover of Ebony magazine of 50,000 March on Montgomery., May 1965.; (Photocopy) (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - List of photographs., June 7-October 17, 1960. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1966. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - List of photographs., March 22-December 10, 1967. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1967. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - List of photographs., January 5-December 17, 1968. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1968. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - List of photographs., January 10-November 18, 1969. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1969. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - List of photographs., July 20-October 22, 1970. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1970. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - List of photographs., May 14-May 17, 1971. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1971. (Box 38, Folder 7)
- Ralph J. Bunche with Famous People., [Box 38, 1 folder]
  - Mostly copy prints of photographs. Some photocopies of photographs., 1940s-1970, bulk. (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Ralph J. Bunche with Eleanor Roosevelt at award dinner at the Waldorf Astoria., 1949 May 9. (Box 38, Folder 8)
- Photographs (Untitled)., [Box 38, 1 folder]
  - Copy prints of photographs, including R.J. Bunche's UN office., 1950s-1970. (Box 38, Folder 9)
- Urquhart Notes about Photographs., [Box 38, 1 folder]
  - Information for photographs for B.E. Urquhart's book., 1875-1992. (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Description of photographs., 1932-1970. (Box 38, Folder 10)
    Includes photographs at UCLA checked against UN photographs, 1947-1949.
  - Photocopies of photographs., 1875-1992, bulk. (Box 38, Folder 10)
- Photographs of Ralph J. Bunche's Immediate Family., [Box 38, 1 folder]
  - Copy prints of photographs. (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Ralph J. Bunche and family disembarking KLM flight., 1963. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Negative of family portrait. (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Post card of family outing to London Zoo., 1937. (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Color slides. (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper clipping photo of Jane Bunche's wedding. (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Original photographs of Jane and Joan as children., 1932-1971, bulk. (Box 38, Folder 11)
- Photographs of Ralph J. Bunche., [Box 38, 1 folder]
  - Copy prints of photographs., 1909-1969. (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Ralph J. Bunche at the United Nations., ca. 1960. (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Ralph J. Bunche with Bernie in St. Louis., 1939 September. (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Ralph J. Bunche at Howard University commencement., 1932 June 10. (Box 38, Folder 12)
      Ralph J. Bunche standing on Commencement Way; Howard University Campus Administration Building in the background.
- Photographs of Ralph J. Bunche's Family., [Box 38, 1 folder]
  - R.J. Bunche & family negatives made from prints. (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - 2 photos of R.J. Bunche as child., (3 × 5 wallet) (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Ralph J. Bunche, portrait at around age 6., ca. 1910. (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Photos of R.J. Bunche w/Grace, Charles, Alma Johnson, & Ethel Johnson & his mother. (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Ralph J. Bunche and Grace Bunche on steps., 1914 Spring. (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Ethel Johnson, Ralph J. Bunche, Alma Dreyfus Johnson, and Grace Bunche (seated)., ca. 1920. (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Photo of Nana at age 50. (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Handwritten notes about photos. (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Copy prints and original prints of photographs., 1800s-1950s. (Box 38, Folder 13)
- Biographical Notes, Early Life, Family., [Box 39, 8 folders]
  - Various biographical accounts, early years. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Biographical notes on R.J. Bunche. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Handwritten letter to R.J. Bunche from his aunt., June 26, 1955. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Handwritten letter to R.J. Bunche & Ruth from Nelle., January 4, 1968. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Letter: R.J. Bunche - Jane., August 11, 1969. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Ralph's questions about Nana. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Biographical articles on R.J. Bunche. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - R.J. Bunche's Anecdotes., 1904-1971. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - R.J.B. family background. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Record of the Johnson family written in., 1953. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Excerpts from letters/memoirs from R.J. Bunche's aunts. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - R.J. Bunche's Notes on Family. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Letter: Bruner/Jane Taylor., October 20, 1973. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - interview with J. Taylor., August 21, 1989. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Letters: Ruth-Jane (); Miss Mann-Jane (); Rev. A.W. Bunche-R.J. Bunche ()., August 10, 1973 September 25, 1975 September 30, 1969. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clipping., September 18, 1949. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Original letters - Nelle Bunche. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - R.J. Bunche's family genealogy., 1810-1964. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Family history. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Bunche family history by Jane., 1830s-1890. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Letters: H. Walker-J. Taylor (); handwritten Jane-R.J. Bunche ()., April 7, 1972 December 10, 1962. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Requiem for Aunt Nelle J. Smith., July 6, 1975. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Tribute to Aunt Nelle. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Excerpts Nelle & Grace letters., 1939-1963. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Copy prints of photos of letters to T.L. Johnson., April 28, 1921 & May 14, 1921. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Transcript of Lamp Unto My Feet Program no.8., November 20, 1949.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Bunche; Ruth, Ralph Jr., Jane, & children. (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - The Man Who Stops Fights H.E. & K. Pringle. Saturday Evening Post., August 13, 1949. (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Pamphlet: service to celebrate life of Ruth H. Bunche., October 11, 1988. (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Original press clipping re Karen B. Pierce's wedding New York Times ()., September 23, 1956 September 19, 1989. (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Article re J. Pierce's spurning drugs. New York Times., January 31, 1989. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Biographical information. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Unitar News (vol.5 no.1)., 1973. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Biographical notes on R.J. Bunche., 1970. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Confidential notes on 14th Meeting of the Committee of Seven., May 7, 1968. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Pamphlet: Ralph Bunche 1904-1971 by B.E. Urquhart., January 1972. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - The Crisis: R.J. Bunche: Odyssey of a statesman., January 1972. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Original New York Times article R.J. Bunche Recalled: The Laurels Wear Well., May 7, 1986. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence from Carter Goodrich to Frances Perkins regarding Bunche., 1944. (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Biographical accounts. (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 1: R.J. Bunche: UN Peacekeeper by P. Mann., 1975. (Box 39, Folder 6)